Visio 2010: XML Schema Definition (XSD) files

XML Schema is a standard recommended by the World Wide Web Consortium (W3C). An XML schema defines the set of tags in an XML document and the rules for applying them. Schemas define the structure and type of data that each data element in a document can contain. Anyone can create a schema to define and qualify the content for their application. This download contains the XML Schema Definition (XSD) files for the Microsoft Visio 2010 XML Drawing (.vdx) format. 

The Microsoft Visio 2010 XML Drawing (.vdx) format is a combination of the following three schema namespaces.

	▪ http://schemas.microsoft.com/visio/2003/core
	▪ http://schemas.microsoft.com/visio/2006/extension
	▪ http://schemas.microsoft.com/office/visio/2010/extension

The first namespace defines the elements used in the Microsoft Visio 2003 XML Drawing format. The other namespaces define the extensions to the original 2003 namespace for the Microsoft Visio 2007 and 2010 XML Drawing formats, respectively. This download contains the XSD files that define these namespaces.

	▪ visio.xsd
	▪ visio12.xsd
	▪ visio14.xsd

The combination of these XSD files defines the DatadiagramML Schema for Visio 2010. For more information about the DatadiagramML Schema, see the Visio 2010 XML Schema Reference (http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ff768724.aspx) in the MSDN Library. The Visio 2010 XML Schema Reference is also included with the Visio 2010 SDK, which is available as a free download at the following URL:

	▪ http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/en/details.aspx?FamilyID=1cdbb7e7-6bd4-488f-91bd-7bd732dbf378

The XSD files in this download can also be used with the Visio 2007 and 2003 XML Drawing formats.


Legal notice

Permission to copy, display, and distribute the contents of this document (the Specification), in any medium for any purpose without fee or royalty is hereby granted, provided that you include the following notice on ALL copies of the Specification, or portions thereof, that you make:

© 2011 Microsoft Corporation. All rights reserved. Permission to copy, display, and distribute this document is available at: http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/hh125898.aspx.

No right to create modifications or derivatives of this Specification is granted herein.

THE SPECIFICATION IS PROVIDED "AS IS" AND MICROSOFT MAKES NO REPRESENTATIONS OR WARRANTIES, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, NON-INFRINGEMENT, OR TITLE; THAT THE CONTENTS OF THE SPECIFICATION ARE SUITABLE FOR ANY PURPOSE; NOR THAT THE IMPLEMENTATION OF SUCH CONTENTS WILL NOT INFRINGE ANY THIRD PARTY PATENTS, COPYRIGHTS, TRADEMARKS, OR OTHER RIGHTS.

MICROSOFT WILL NOT BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES ARISING OUT OF OR RELATING TO ANY USE OR DISTRIBUTION OF THE SPECIFICATION.

The name and trademarks of Microsoft may NOT be used in any manner, including advertising or publicity pertaining to the Specification or its contents without specific, written prior permission. Title to copyright in the Specification will at all times remain with Microsoft.

No other rights are granted by implication, estoppel, or otherwise.

